Kurt Reynertson Papers on Squatters' Rights TAM.335
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Kurt Reynertson Papers on Squatters' Rights
circa 1980s-1990s
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Reynertson, Kurt A.
TAM.335
2 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Kurt A. Reynertson in 2006. The accession number associated with this gift is 2006.005.
Historical/Biographical Note
Kurt Reynertson is a plant science biologist and a founding member of the Brooklyn Artist Alliance. As one of the squatters at the 537-539 East 5th Street squat, he was involved in legal proceedings against the City of New York after a fire damaged the building. The case was closed in 1997 after the plaintiffs were awarded damages.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of legal documents pertaining to the suit against the city, as well as press clippings and a number of videotapes.
PLEASE DIRECT FURTHER INQUIRIES TO: tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access DVDs for audiovisual materials in the collection are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only.
Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.); Squatters -- New York (State) -- New York; Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.) -- Social conditions.; Reynertson, Kurt A.
- 5th Street Squat, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 537-539 E 5th Street: Related Documents, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Affidavits, Verifications, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Amended Petition - Contempt, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Claim Againts Department of Buildings, New York City, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Clippings, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Department of Buildings: Emergency Declaration Form, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Emergency Affirmation - Contempt, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Fact Patterns, Building Diagrams, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Finances, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Financial Documents, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Fire Report, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Legal Documents, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Newspapers, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 13A)
- Handwritten Notes, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Soccoza Testimony, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Stipulation of Settlement, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Supreme Court: 537-539 East 5th Street: Transcripts, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Supreme Court: 537-539 East 5th Street: Transcripts/2, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Supreme Court: 537-539 East 5th Street: Transcripts/3, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Supreme Court: 537-539 East 5th Street: Transcripts/20, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder data_value_missing_9b50b7c9d8fa8f9d9eacd2e195949276)
- Supreme Court: 537-539 East 5th Street: Transcripts and Related Materials, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Supreme Court: 537-539 East 5th Street: Interrogation Transcripts/1, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Supreme Court: 537-539 East 5th Street: Interrogation Transcripts/2, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Supreme Court: 537-539 East 5th Street: Barbara Capnick's Decision, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Landlord Blues by Jacob Burckhardt, 1987 (Box 2, Cassette TAM.335_ref43, Dvd TAM.335_ref43)
- 13th Street Squat - Spagnolo, May 29-30 and July 4, 1995 (Box 2, Cassette TAM.335_ref35, Dvd TAM.335_ref35, Box Digitized Access Files, File TAM.335_ref35)
- Diva TV - Squatters Footage, May 30, 1995 (Box 2, Cassette TAM.335_ref41, Dvd TAM.335_ref41, Box Digitized Access Files, File TAM.335_ref41)
- Overview of East 13th Street/Avenue B (1 of 4), May 30, 1995 (Box 2, Cassette TAM.355_ref37, Dvd TAM.355_ref37, Box Digitized Access Files, File TAM.355_ref37)
- 2 of 4, May 30, 1995 (Box 2, Cassette TAM.355_ref38, Dvd TAM.355_ref38, Box Digitized Access Files, File TAM.355_ref38)
- The Eviction of the East 13th Street Homesteaders Coalition Buildings 545 541 539, May 30, 1995 (Box 2, Cassette TAM.335_ref42, Dvd TAM.335_ref42)
- Eviction: Tape 1 NPK, 13th Street and Avenue B, May 30, 1995 (Box 2, Cassette TAM.335_ref44, Dvd TAM.335_ref44, Box Digitized Access Files, File TAM.335_ref44)
- Evictions 13th Street/Avenue B (3 of 4), May 30, 1995 (Box 2, Cassette TAM.335_ref39, Dvd TAM.335_ref39, Box Digitized Access Files, File TAM.335_ref39)
- Evictions 13th Street/Avenue B (4 of 4), May 30, 1995 (Box 2, Cassette TAM.335_ref40, Dvd TAM.335_ref40, Box Digitized Access Files, File TAM.335_ref40)
- Network Coverage - East 13th Street Squat Eviction, May 30, 1995 (Box 2, Cassette TAM.335_ref28)
- New York City Department of Buildings - 539/541/545 East 13th Street, Manhattan, May 30, 1995 (Box 2, Cassette TAM.335_ref31, Dvd TAM.335_ref31, Box Digitized Access Files, File TAM.335_ref31)
- First East Coast Micropower Radio Conference - Friday Night Panel with the FCC, Mar 3, 1998 (Box 2, Cassette TAM.335_ref32, Dvd TAM.335_ref32, Box Digitized Access Files, File TAM.335_ref32)
- Nippon Television, Spagnolo, "Zoom In!! ASA!", undated (Box 2, Cassette TAM.335_ref36, Dvd TAM.335_ref36)
- "Squat or Rot" (Work in progress, 20:00 minutes), undated (Box 2, Cassette TAM.335_ref34, Dvd TAM.335_ref34, Box Digitized Access Files, File TAM.335_ref34)